Inventory of the Page-Saunders Papers 1790-1932
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Page-Saunders Papers 1790-1932
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Mss. 39.1 P15
190 items.
Correspondence and papers of members of the Page and Saunders families.
Page Family,; Saunders Family.
Administrative Information
Restrictions on Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
Purchase: 109 items, 1938.
Biographical/Historical Information
Robert Saunders was born 25 January 1805 in Williamsburg, Virginia. He attended the College of William and Mary and the University of Virginia. Saunders served as professor of mathematics at William and Mary from 1833 to 1848 and was president of the college 1847-1848. He was a captain in the Confederate States Army, head of Eastern State Hospital, mayor of Willamsburg, vestryman of Bruton Parish and served in the Virginia State Senate. Saunders married Lucy Burwell Page in 1828 and had, among other children, Roberta Saunders and Robert Page Saunders. He died 11 September 1868.
Scope and Content Information
This collection includes correspondence of Margaret Lowther Page of "Rosewell," Gloucester County, Virginia and Williamsburg, Virginia with her daughter Lucy Burwell Page Saunders and her son-in-law Robert Saunders. Also included are a diary, 1826, of Robert Saunders while on a trip from New York to Le Havre; published stories of Lucy Burwell Page Saunders; manuscript stories by Roberta Saunders; and correspondence of Robert Page Saunders.
There are references to Benjamin Stoddert Ewell and to the College of William and Mary in the papers; a letter, 16 February 1816, written by William Wirt to Robert Saunders; and letters from Sally M. Galt of Williamsburg.
Arrangement
Organization
This collection is organized into 4 Series. Series 1 contains Correspondence; Series 2 contains papers concerning estates; Series 3 contains writtings; and Series 4 contains miscellaneous material.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged mostly chronologically.
Index Terms
Persons:
Page, Margaret Lowther.; Saunders, Lucy Burwell Page, 1807- 1886.; Saunders, Robert; Saunders, Roberta, d. 1894.; Saunders, Robert, 1845-1925.; Galt, Sally M.; Ewell, Benjamin Stoddert, 1810- 1894.
Family Names
Page family.; Saunders family.
Subjects>
Williamsburg (Va.)--History--19th century.; College of William and Mary--History--19th century.
Contents List
  Series 1: Correspondence
- Correspondence, 1790-1933 and n.d.
  - Letters, 1790-1865. (Folder 1)
    - William Nelson, Jr. York [County, Virginia], to Robert Saunders, 2 March 1790., 2 pages on 1 leaf. ALS. (Folder 1)
      Lawsuits and money owed.
    - William Clairborne, at Richmond, to Robert Saunders, at Williamsburg, 18 August 1790., 2 pages on 1 leaf. ALS. (Folder 1)
      Escape of Yarbrough who owes money to Blair from jail. Willing to give Yarbrough a year longer if can get deed of trust.
    - Margaret Page, at Rosewell, [Gloucester County, Virginia], to her sister, Mrs. McLaine, at Edenton, North Carolina, 22 February 1796., 3 pages on one leaf. Bears seal. (Folder 1)
      Death of her sister's fiance. Can't visit but entreats sister to come to her to live. Arrival of General Wayne in Philadelphia. Can she get a letter to sister Penny and Mr. Dawson. Health of her children, Gregory and Peggy.
    - William Wirt, at Richmond, to Robert Saunders, at Williamsburg. Encloses W. B. Cabell's bond (not present), 16 February 1816., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 1)
    - Margaret Page, Williamsburg, to Mrs. Lowther, at Edenton, North Carolina, March 18, 1818. (Folder 1)
      Sister. Illness of her poor Barbara. Peggy helped. 4 children. Herrings. Dr and Mrs. Sawyer. Unhappy by late proceedings of President and Professors. General impression their conduct equally reprehensible as that of the students. Sorry Samuel signed remonstrance. She would have tried to stop him. Boards with Mr. Tazewell. Piece in Enquirer. Mrs. Byrd's accounts of lots in Lynchburg. Will retract two words. Note: This letter refers to the reprehensible conduct of the faculty and students of William and Mary College.
    - Margaret Page, Williamsburg, to Mrs. Lowther, at Edenton, North Carolina, September 17, 1818. (Folder 1)
      Margaret Page, Williamsburg, to Mrs. Lowther, at Edenton, North Carolina. Worried re: her. Death of Chancellor Nelson. My John visiting springs. Lucy, Barbara and myself went to Gloster [Gloucester County, Virginia] Expectation of visiting Peggy. Waiting for payment for Grain sale. Lucy delighted at thoughts of visiting William. Dr. Hare appointed Professor of Chemistry at Medical College at Philadelphia. Dear William, Maria and Mr. Skinner.[illegible SAR handwriting] Mr. Skinner returned here.
    - Margaret Page, at Williamsburg, to Mrs. Lowther, at Edenton, North Carolina, 16 April 1819., 3 pages on 1 leaf. (Folder 1)
      Birth of Maria's Skinner child. Condition of her shoulder that was operated on 12 years before. Invites her and our dear William to visit. Daughter Barbara has returned from Richmond and granddaughter Peggy, tho unable to walk is thought by physicians to be in a fair way of perfect recovery. Rest of her children quite well.
    - Margaret Page, at Elmington, [Gloucester County], to Mrs. Lowther, at Edenton, North Carolina, 23 September 1819. (Folder 1)
    - Margaret Page, Williamsburg, to Mrs. Lowther, at Edenton, North Carolina, 13 August 1819. (Folder 1)
      Death of Mrs. Henry Skipwith. (Elizabeth Byrd). Extreme heat. Son has left.
    - Margaret Page, at Elmington, [Gloucester County], to Mrs. Lowther, at Edenton, North Carolina, 23 September 1819., 3 pages on 1 leaf. (Folder 1)
      Her sister's health. At Elmington visiting daughter. Granddaughter Peggy still unable to use leg. Son John has situated at Union Town, Monroe County, Virginia near White and Sweet Sulphur Springs. Disappointed to hear from Mr. Blair that Mr. Skinner has been in Richmond and she had not seen him. "Lucy is delighted at the thought of having William's picture...wishes above all things to see the little Penelope." "Present us most affectionately to our beloved Maria and William... Kiss for us all the sweet little Pen."
    - Margaret Page, at Williamsburg, to her son, John Page, at Union Town, Monroe County, Virginia, 19 January 1820, 4 pages on 1 leaf. (Folder 1)
      "... as I am sensible of the deep Interest you take in our dear Lucy's improvement, hasten to inform you that on the 11th Mr. Morse (the gentleman who boarded at Mrs. Peachy's open'd a school for the education of young ladies... "Mr. Fontaine ... had much skill in gardening and publish'd a garden calendar for every Month in the Year a Manuscript Copy of which I ought to have among my Papers. The great Botanist Clayton of whom you also enquire was well known to your Father... He resided either in gloster or Middlesex... I heard the remains of his Garden frequently spoken of, as being at no great Distance... " Mr. Clayton's grandson. Death of Mrs. Andrews and terms of her will. Tuckers are relieved from anxiety on Mrs. Cabell's account. Sally Tazewell to be married to Mr. Goode. Mayo advertised the revised code and as I requested Mr. Blair (he having both Cooper Jemmy's and Wison's hire for the last year in his hands) to get and pay for the copy I engaged and send it on to you.
    - S. G. P. Saratoga to Cousin Miss Lucy B. Page, Williamsburg, Virginia, 21 May 1827., 2 pages on 1 leaf. (Folder 1)
      Glad to hear people in Williamsburg interested in religion. Would like more rhymes from E. G. G.
    - Robert Saunders, at Williamsburg, to William P. Saunders, at New York, 18 June 1835., 3 pages on 1 leaf. (Folder 1)
      Appreciates his sympathy at death of his father (William's uncle). Bequest under will. Left money and watch with chain and one seal.
    - [? Page], at Williamsburg, to Mrs. Lucy B. Saunders, at Staunton, Virginia Margaret Page to her daughter, Mrs. Lucy B. Saunders. [Barbara Page] to her sister, Mrs. Lucy B. Saunders, 12 August 1835. (Folder 1)
      Trial of Dr. Ducachet (Episcopal minister).
    - Margaret Page to her daughter, Mrs. Lucy B. Saunders, at Staunton, [Augusta County, Virginia], August 14, 1835. (Folder 1)
      Rains. Thunder cloud. Dr. Ducachet honorably acquitted. Horrible mob in Baltimore. [note says one of last letters Margaret Lowther Page wrote]
    - R[obert] S[aunders], at Williamsburg, to Mrs. Robert Saunders, at Bowling Green, Caroline County, 1 August 1838. (Folder 1)
      Pleased at continued recovery of daughter. Dr. P at Jamestown. Cannot get away due to accident with boat to return to Bowling Green where daughter, Sally Cary is ill. Health of friends in Williamsburg. Hot, hot weather there.
    - L. A. Page, at Greenland, [Gloucester County], to Misses Page, at Williamsburg, 13 May 1853. (Folder 1)
      Clothes she is sewing and clothes she is sending. Mentions what others have been wearing. Fears confinement of teaching will be too much for you.
    - Aunt Barbara Page, at Staunton, to Page [Saunders?], 25 September 1860. (Folder 1)
      Has been to hear Cousin Robert Nelson preach. Staunton Institute opens tomorrow. Mrs. Forest has female teacher from the North who taught in Mississippi and Memphis and knew Kate Millington... she is keeping a boy's school but it is in town at the Academy."
    - Robert Saunders, at Williamsburg, to his son [Robert Page Saunders], 13 May 1861, 4 pages on 1 leaf. (Folder 1)
      Three fortifications going up in our immediate neighborhood. Blockade in Virginia. College closed two days ago. Description of defenses at Gloucester Point, Yorktown and Jamestown. Blockade intended to worry people out of a vote for secession. Ewell has commenced erection of plank huts on field on College Landing road. Typescript available.
    - Robert Saunders, at Williamsburg, to R[obert] P[age] Saunders, 13 November 1861., 4 pages on 1 leaf. (Folder 1)
      Is no longer president of the railroad. Mr. Wilmer is chaplain of Ewell's regiment. Professor Morrison died of typhoid fever. Corrects his French.
    - Robert Saunders, at Richmond, to [his daughter], Lelia L. Saunders, 1 February 1863. (Folder 1)
      Has had place in Treasury Dept. conferred on him. Not pleased with position but friends worked so hard to get it for him, he will keep it for awhile to see if he can advance. Mrs. Minnigerode remains unwell.
    - Robert Saunders, at Richmond, to Lelia [L.] Saunders, 4 March 1863., 4 pages on 1 leaf. (Folder 1)
      Bad weather. Mrs. General Gaines. Has not seen Lizzie Ewell but has seen Mr. Stoddert.
    - Robert Saunders, at Richmond, to his son, [Robert Page Saunders], 22 March 1863. (Folder 1)
      Son's demerits at Virginia Military Institute.
    - Robert Saunders, at Richmond, to his wife, [Lucy Page Saunders], 19 April 1863., 2 pages on 1 leaf. (Folder 1)
      Wise is a little above Williamsburg. Probably not going to attack Fort Magruder. Col. Tabb's skirmish at Whitaker's Mill. Went around Williamsburg and Fort Magruder by way of Tutter's Neck. Could have taken Fort Magruder earlier. Mrs. Morison's porch hit by shell.
    - Robert Saunders, at Pittsylvania Court House, to Robert Page Saunders, 18 May 1863., 2 pages on 1 leaf. (Folder 1)
      Has sent money to Gen. Smith. Yankees retook possession of Williamsburg after Gen. Wise left it.
    - R[obert] S[aunders], at Richmond, to his wife, [Lucy Page Saunders], 24 May 1863. (Folder 1)
      Invited to get some of Miss Rebecca's good tea. Visited General Ewell who is installed on house on Franklin Street near Eighth and just opposite Mrs. Stanard's. Found Lizzie there.
    - Robert Saunders, at Richmond, to his daughter, Page Saunders, 10 June 1863., 2 pages on 1 leaf. (Folder 1)
      Has visited Ewells.
    - [Robert Saunders], at Richmond, to his wife, [Lucy Page Saunders], 22 June 1863., Incomplete. (Folder 1)
      Description of Ashland. Visit to the household of Bishop Johns and lists who lives there. Has been offered new position (quartermaster).
    - R[obert] S[aunders], at Liberty, [Bedford County], to his daughter, Lelia Saunders, 7 August 1863. (Folder 1)
      Description of his travels in his new position as quartermaster collecting taxes.
    - R[obert] S[aunders], at Williamsburg, to Lelia [Saunders], 10 August 1865. (Folder 1)
      Wants pardon, land back and something to do.
  - Letters, 1873-1933. (Folder 2)
    - Sally M. Galt, at Williamsburg, to Robert [Page Saunders], 3 October 1873. (Folder 2)
      Celebration of 100th anniversary of Asylum will be 12 October 1873. First patient admitted.
    - Sally M. Galt, at Williamsburg, to Mrs. [Lucy Page] Saunders, 13 October 1873., Incomplete. (Folder 2)
      Sends enclosed [invitations to Robert?] Description of wedding.
    - Sally M. Galt to [?], 10 November 1873. (Folder 2)
      Invites someone to be guest.
    - Sally M. Galt to [?], 14 July 1874. (Folder 2)
      News of friends. Dick Coke to be senator from Texas. Description of wedding.
    - S[ally] M. Galt, at Williamsburg, Virginia, to [Mrs. Lucy Page Saunders], 14 July 1876. (Folder 2)
    - S. M. Galt, at Richmond, Virginia, to [Mrs. Lucy Page Saunders], 16 January 1877. (Folder 2)
      Bad weather. Leonora. Death of Mary Booth. Death of Alice Brown Hammond, nee Hankins.
    - S. M. Galt, at Williamsburg, to [Mrs. Lucy Page Saunders], 17 September 1879. (Folder 2)
      Gabriella is too sick to attend to putting up the stone.
    - L[ucy] B[urwell] S[aunders], at Louise Home, [Washington, D.C.], to her son Robert L.P. Saunders, at Baltimore, Maryland, 1 March 1880. (Folder 2)
      "Says Dr. Power wrote to ask her to let Jno. Tyler and his daughter rent rooms in the house but she refused. What can he want there I wonder. He was so intemperate in this city before he left and had his daughter with him." Wants him to contact publisher in Baltimore to see if he would put story for Indian mission of Bp. Whipple.
    - Sally M. Galt, at Williamsburg, Virginia, to Mrs. Lucy Page Saunders, 24 June 1880. (Folder 2)
      Delia Braithwaite and her flock. Kindness of Braithwaites to her in her illness. Intends to be in Baltimore on the 11th. Visit from Rev. William Pettus of Kentucky. Protege of Prof. Ro. Saunders. Mrs. Minnegerode has sent me the dr's. sermons.
    - L[ucy] B[urwell] S[aunders], at Louise Home, [Washington, D.C.], to her son [Robert L.P. Saunders], 1 October 1880. (Folder 2)
    - Henry B. Michie, at Macaria, to Robert Saunders, 24 December 1882. (Folder 2)
      Appreciate subscription to the Nation.(Christmas present.)
    - L[ucy] B[urwell] S[aunders], at Yorktown, to Page [Saunders], 30 June 1883. (Folder 2)
      Visits. Hard times in Williamsburg. Even in Yorktown vegetables and ice very high. Food is scarce in Williamsburg. Lack of money.
    - M.J. Griffin, at Hickory Fork, [Gloucester County], to Robert [Saunders], 27 December 1883. (Folder 2)
      Thanks for Life of Caesar. Burning of house at Shelly.
    - Cornelia F. Taylor, at Viareggio, Toscana, Italy, to Mrs. Saunders, December 1884., Elaborate letterhead. (Folder 2)
      Cholera epidemic. Illness of family. Uncle. His son "our poor feeble-minded one is of course a great charge.
    - James Weaver, at Boston, Miss [Page] Saunders, 4 March 1886. (Folder 2)
      Has brought place in Hampton.
    - Elizabeth S. Ewell, at Georgetown, D.C., to Page Saunders, 12 September 1888. (Folder 2)
      Has dispatched sketch. Want of means makes no difference in the Southern manners. Lizzie wrote that Ewell has gone to Texas. Neither herself or her father like it. Mr. Soctt does on Ewell's account.
    - Philemon H. Tuck, at Baltimore, to Robert P. Saunders, at Baltimore, 4 February 1907. (Folder 2)
      Mortgage rates.
    - Lycett, at Baltimore, Maryland, to R. P. Saunders, at Baltimore, 2 October 1913. (Folder 2)
      Subscription to Maryland Churchman. Enclosure: An advertisement of Lycett, stationer.
    - Laura N. Mann, at Washington, D.C., to R. P. Saunders, at Baltimore, Maryland, 12 November 1918., Telegram. (Folder 2)
      Death of Mrs. Capron.
    - John MacKaye Dunbar, at Washington, D.C., to Robert Saunders, at Baltimore, Maryland, 28 April 1919. (Folder 2)
      Thanks for bread and cheese. Received iron.
    - Annie M. Baker, Baltimore, Maryland, to Robert P. Saunders, at Baltimore, Maryland, 6 September 1919. (Folder 2)
      Payment for mortgage.
    - [John] Mac[Kaye Dunbar], at Washington, D.C., to Robert Page Saunders, at Baltimore, Maryland, 5 December 1919. (Folder 2)
      Wants to hear from him concerning his health.
    - Annie M. Baker, Baltimore, Maryland, to Robert P. Saunders, 10 December 1919 (Folder 2)
      Carmody mortgage.
    - [John] Mac[Kaye Dunbar], to [Robert Page] Saunders, 29 December 1919. (Folder 2)
      Glad he feels so well. Wishes they could send box of eats and check.
    - M. W. Mercer, Louise Home, [Washington, D.C.], to Lucy Page [Poindexter], 27 August 1933., 8 pages on four leaves. (Folder 2)
      Afraid she has mislead Lucy Page concerning her health statement. Talks about what her health statement said. Good health for my age.
  - Letters, undated. (Folder 3)
    - Lucy [Poindexter], at Buchanan, [Botetourt County], Virginia, to Robert P. Saunders, at Baltimore, Maryland, n.d. (Folder 3)
      Lucy teaching in Fincastle. Wants Page book. Jack Munford's death.
    - Lelia [Saunders], at Richmond, to her mother, [Lucy Page Saunders], n.d. (Folder 3)
    - Lelia [Saunders], at Chatham, to her sister, Page [Saunders], n.d. (Folder 3)
    - Lelia [Saunders], at Oaklands, [Frederick County, Virginia], to Page Saunders, n.d. (Folder 3)
    - L[ucy] B[urwell] S[aunders], at Severn View, [Gloucester County, Virginia], to Page Saunders, at Fincastle, Botetourt County, Virginia, n.d. (Folder 3)
    - L[ucy] B[urwell] S[aunders], at Louise Home, [Washington, D.C.], to her son Robert Leslie P. Saunders, n.d., 6 letters. 1 postcard. (Folder 3)
    - Page [Saunders], at Lexington, to Robert [Saunders], n.d. (Folder 3)
    - Page [Saunders], at Georgetown, to Robert L. P. Saunders, at Baltimore, Maryland, n.d. (Folder 3)
    - Page [Saunders], at Washington, to Robert [Saunders], n.d. (Folder 3)
    - Robert Saunders, at Williamsburg, to [his daughter], Lelia Louisa Saunders, at Bowling Green, [Caroline County, Virginia], n.d. (Folder 3)
    - R[obert] S[aunders] to [his wife, Lucy Page Saunders], n.d., Incomplete. (Folder 3)
    - Robert Saunders, at Williamsburg, to his daughter, Margaret P. Saunders, at Bowling Green, [Caroline County, Virginia], n.d. (Folder 3)
    - Lizzie [i.e. Elizabeth Scott], at Williamsburg, to Page [Saunders], n.d. (Folder 3)
    - Elizabeth Williams to Miss Lucy [?], n.d. (Folder 3)
    - Emma [?] to [Mrs. L. W. Poindexter], n.d. (Folder 3)
    - [?], at Elk Hill, to Page [Saunders], n.d., Incomplete. (Folder 3)
    - n.d., Incomplete. (Folder 3)
    - Portions of letter probably from Sally M. Galt to Mrs. Lucy Page Saunders, n.d., 5 items. (Folder 3)
    - One unidentified letter, n.d., Incomplete. (Folder 3)
  Series 2: Papers Concerning Estates
- Papers Concerning Estates, 1887-1925., 3 items. (Folder 4)
  - Saunders (Mrs. Lucy B. P.) Administrator's account, 1887., 3 items. (Folder 4)
  - Saunders (Robert P), 1925., 2 letters. (Folder 4)
  - Saunders (Roberta Page), 1894-1900., 10 items. (Folder 4)
    Includes will.
  Series 3: Writings
- Writings, 1872-1876. (Folder 5)
  - Writings of Mrs. Lucy Page Saunders, 1872-1876. (Folder 5)
    - Leonora and the ghost...Baltimore, Charles Harvey & Co., 1876., 23 pages. 18.5 cm. (Folder 5)
    - Dora Leee or the visit to Montpelier...Baltimore, Charles Harvey & Co., 1872., 83 pages. 15.5 cm. (Folder 5)
      Note: Signature of Robert P. Saunders on back of front cover and on fly leaf.
  - Writings of Miss Roberta Page Saunders, n.d. (Folder 5)
    - A lost picture, n.d., 8 sheets. Manuscript. (Folder 5)
      Also a newspaper clipping of an article by B. J. Lossing regarding the subject of this picture which hung in the library of Robert Saunders of Williamsburg, Virginia. 1 item.
    - Was it only a dream, n.d., 6 sheets. Manuscript. (Folder 5)
    - The doll's wedding and a Virginia war episode, n.d., 12 pages. Manuscript. (Folder 5)
  - An incomplete manuscript of a short story by an unknown person, n.d. (Folder 5)
  - Margaret Lowther Page: Journal & Poems, 1790.
  Series 4: Miscellaneous
- Miscellaneous, 1813-1879. (Folder 6)
  - War of 1812 Documents, 1813. (Folder 6)
    - Muster roll of troop of cavalry under the command of Captain Robert Saunders, 1813., 1 item. (Folder 6)
    - Inspection return of Captain Robert Saunders' Williamsburg volunteers, 1813., 1 item. (Folder 6)
  - Accounts of John Stafford of Giles County, Virginia, 1818-1833., 2 items. (Folder 6)
  - Diary of Robert Saunders, Jr., 1826., 68 pages of which 28 were used. 6.25 x 4 inches. (Folder 6)
  - Wills, 1834-1836. (Folder 6)
    - Copy of the will of Robert Saunders, 1834., 1 item. (Folder 6)
    - Copy of the will of John Page, 1836., 1 item. (Folder 6)
  - Certificate of appointment of Robert Saunders as a director of the Eastern Lunatic Asylum. 1851., 1 item. (Folder 6)
  - Obituaries 1866-1868. (Folder 6)
    - Papers concerning death of Lelia Saunders, 1866-1867. (Folder 6)
      - Obituaries of Lelia Saunders, 1866., 2 items. (Folder 6)
      - Reflections by [Mrs. Lucy Page Saunders] upon the death of Lelia Sanders, 1867., 1 item. (Folder 6)
    - Papers concerning the death of Robert Saunders, 1868. (Folder 6)
      - Obituary of Robert Saunders, [1868]., 1 item. (Folder 6)
      - Resolutions upon the death of Robert Saunders, [d. September 11, 1868?]. 1868., 2 items. (Folder 6)
      - Tribute to Robert Saunders, 1868., 1 item. (Folder 6)
        This tribute is written on the flyleaf of a copy of the Book of Common Prayer.
      - Reflections on the death of M.H. Lawrence, sister of Robert Saunders, n.d. (Folder 6)
  - Copyright certificate of the book Dora Lee by L. Page Saunders, 1872. (Folder 6)
  - Deed given by the College of William and Mary to Lucy B. Saunders covering a portion of a lot in Williamsburg, 1872. (Folder 6)
  - Newspaper clipping from the Sunday Herald, Washington D.C., 1873 (Folder 6)
    Concerns William W. Corcoran.
  - Pencil sketch of the house in which Mariane [Saunders] Wilmer lived, n.d. (Folder 6)
  - Genealogical notes, n.d., 2 items. (Folder 7)
  - Greeting cards, n.d. (Folder 7)
  - Verse, n.d., 10 items. (Folder 7)
    Includes a book of quotations which probably belonged to Mrs. Lucy Page Saunders.
  - Other papers, n.d., 26 items. (Folder 7)
    Includes memorandum book.
  - Photographs and prints, n.d., 15 items. (Folder 7)
  - Fragments and envelopes, n.d., 6 items. (Folder 7)
  - Margaret Lowther's copy of Poems on Several Occasions, n.d., In fragile condition. Titlepage torn. (Folder 7)
    Written by Dr. Thomas Parnell, Late Arch-Deacon of Clogher and published by Mrs. Pope.